<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2020-02-16T13:46:38-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Technical Debt is Soul-crushing</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/technical-debt/"/>
   <updated>2020-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/technical-debt</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Technical debt is incurred when the software or system designers take &lt;strong&gt;short-cuts&lt;/strong&gt; to ship a feature faster, increasing the overall complexity of the system. The goal is to optimize for the present rather than the future. In other words, it’s the easier path that takes us to the end-goal faster but the resulting code (or design) is messy and complicated. It will require extra time in the future to add new features or to fix bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common reason why companies take on technical debt is to meet the time to market demands. “We must release this feature by February, or our revenue will take a big hit. Just hack it for now and we’ll fix it later.” Other reasons for incuring tech debt includes lousy design choices, poor programming, changing requirements or the presence of outdated libraries or frameworks that made sense in the past but have become a liability now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sample blog. Read more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeahoy.com&quot;&gt;CodeAhoy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Do Software Developers Normally Code on Weekends? Work-life Balance and Overtime in the Tech Industry</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/19/do-software-developers-work-weekends-work-life-tech/"/>
   <updated>2019-10-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/19/do-software-developers-work-weekends-work-life-tech</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite all the perks tech companies offer to employees these days (unlimited PTOs, catered lunches, refreshments, beer on tap, dog friendly offices, gyms, yoga classes), there is often an indirect or hidden pressure on software engineers to put in more hours or to code on weekends. Managers say things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You can call me on the weekend or even at night if you have any questions. I will answer your phone because I’ll be working anyways.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Sam is an amazing engineer. So dedicated and such a hardworker. He couldn’t finish his tasks because he was blocked for two days by the other team so he spent all weekend coding.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I’m so proud of my team. They regularly stayed late and worked weekends to deliver on our roadmap.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We’ll be using the new technology XYZ for this project. Why don’t you start learning XYZ in your ‘free time’ (aka the weekend)?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/worked_my_butt_off.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Workaholic_Software_Engineer&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sample blog. Read more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeahoy.com&quot;&gt;CodeAhoy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>GraphQL - A Practical Overview and Hands-On Tutorial</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/13/graphql-practical-tutorial/"/>
   <updated>2019-10-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/13/graphql-practical-tutorial</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;GraphQL is a &lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;uery &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;anguage for APIs. It provides a fresh and &lt;em&gt;modern&lt;/em&gt; approach to fetching (and manipulating) data from APIs when compared to traditional methods such as REST. Its power comes from the ability to let clients talk to a single endpoint and specify exactly what data they need. That’s very powerful indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ed8SzALpx1Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sample blog. Read more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeahoy.com&quot;&gt;CodeAhoy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
